<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>D i o g o D A T A</title><link>https://diogo-dantas.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on D i o g o D A T A</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 06:00:10 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://diogo-dantas.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The impact of implementing a Power BI dashboard on sales and returns analysis</title><link>https://diogo-dantas.github.io/posts/data-viz/power-bi/dash-vendas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 06:00:10 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://diogo-dantas.github.io/posts/data-viz/power-bi/dash-vendas/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a highly competitive sector such as electronics, efficient analysis of sales and returns data is essential for improving processes and boosting store performance. For a fictitious chain of stores, I created a Power BI dashboard with the aim of providing a clear and dynamic view of this data, helping to make more strategic decisions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main task was to transform raw sales and returns data into valuable, strategic information. To do this, I used Power Query in the ETL (Extract, Transform and Load) process from files in XLSX format. This work included detailed cleaning and normalization of the data, structuring it efficiently for analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intelligent management: Shell script integration and task automation</title><link>https://diogo-dantas.github.io/posts/task-automation/shell-script/boutique-manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://diogo-dantas.github.io/posts/task-automation/shell-script/boutique-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>Shell scripts are powerful tools that allow you to automate various tasks on Unix and Linux systems. By encapsulating a series of commands in a single script, it is possible to streamline processes, reduce errors and increase operational efficiency. This versatile programming language makes it easy to manipulate files, automate administrative tasks and provide precise control over the system, making it ideal for a wide range of applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using the knowledge acquired in the course &lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/30JGE2RZY8T4" title="Visit the course certificate" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hands-on Introduction to Linux Commands and Shell Scripting&lt;/a>, I applied the project to a real-world scenario, Boutique Manager, which consists of a shell script management system for small clothing stores.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ETL simplified: unified data</title><link>https://diogo-dantas.github.io/posts/etl/python/etl-simplificado/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://diogo-dantas.github.io/posts/etl/python/etl-simplificado/</guid><description>&lt;p>In today&amp;rsquo;s dynamic business environment, integrating and analysing data from multiple sources is essential for making informed decisions. In many industries, such as finance, logistics or marketing, it is common to receive data files in a variety of formats, including CSV, XML and JSON. These files can contain valuable information, but their dispersion and variety of formats make processing and analysis a significant challenge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the challenges in this scenario is the need to consolidate information from multiple files into a single format that can be easily imported into a database, for example. The task becomes even more critical when considering the need to maintain data integrity and consistency during this compilation process.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>